Guide to the Office of the University Secretary Records, 1924-ongoing UA.04.01.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Office of the University Secretary records
1924-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of the Secretary
UA.04.01.0001
24 Linear Feet
The Office of the University Secretary at Duke University was established by by-law in 1903. The Office evolved with the University and the roles and responsibilities likely shifted from person to person. Today's Office most likely began in 1941 with Charles Jordan. The Secretary is an officer of the University and reports directly to the President. A major role of the Secretary's Office is to coordinate affairs of the Board of Trustees. Records include correspondence with Trustees and Presidents, Honorary Degrees and Search Committees for high-level administrators, reports, volunteer directories, faculty data and photographs, questionnaires and University by-laws. Some materials have been transferred to the Board of Trustees collection.
Access Restrictions
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
Provenance
The Office of the University Secretary Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973-1996, 2008, 2015, and 2018.
Historical Note
The University Secretary is an officer of the University and reports to the President. A major role of the Secretary's Office is to coordinate affairs of the Board of Trustees. The Secretary's Office also tracks the University volunteers program. The position of University Secretary has been held by the following individuals:
Robert L. Flowers, University Secretary, 1926-1940
Charles E. Jordan, University Secretary, 1941-1957
John M. Dozier, University Secretary, 1958-1961
R. L. Predmore, University Secretary, 1962
Craufurd D. Goodwin, University Secretary, 1963-1966
Rufus H. Powell, University Secretary, 1967-1981
Roger L. Marshall, University Secretary, 1982-1986
N. Allison Haltom, University Secretary, 1987-2007
Richard Riddell, 2008-present
Scope and Contents note
The Office of the University Secretary's records includes correspondence, reports, volunteer directories, faculty data and photographs, questionnaires, and University by-laws.
Related Material
Board of Trustees Reference Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Board of Trustees Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Conditions Governing Access
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Conditions Governing Access
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of audiotapes and videotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies. Reference copies for some materials may have been made, and if a reference copy exists, it is noted in this finding aid. To arrange for the creation of reference copies of other items, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Duke University -- Directories; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University. Office of the Secretary; Duke University. Academic Council; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University -- Presidents; Duke University -- Students; Duke University -- Finance; Duke University -- History; Duke University -- Employees; Duke University -- Faculty
- Container List
  - Faculty Biographical Sheets A-F, 1967-1987 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Biographical Sheets G-M, 1967-1987 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Biographical Sheets Mc-V, 1967-1987 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Biographical Sheets W-Z, 1967-1987 (Box 4)
  - University Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1965-1995 (Box 4)
  - Faculty and Staff Disclosure Statements, 1979-1982 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Names for Pictorial Directory, circa 1963 (Box 4)
  - Faculty Appointments, 1963-1984 (Box 5)
  - Full-Time University Faculty by Department, Rank, Degree, Sex, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Statistics: 1983-1987 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Emeriti (Box 5)
  - Faculty Information: Data Processing (Box 5)
  - Undergraduate Faculty Council (Box 5)
  - Faculty Handbook, 1972-1978 (Box 5)
  - Questionnaires, 1968-1981 (Box 6)
  - Questionnaires: Higher Education General Information Survey (HEGIS), 1967-1973 (Box 6)
  - Questionnaires: National Science Foundation, 1971-1975 (Box 6)
  - Higher Educational General Information Survey (HEGIS), 1973-1984 (Box 7)
  - Duke Hospital Financial Reports, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Duke Hospital Modernization and Financial Reports, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Hospital -- Duke, Bylaws, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Financial Feasibility Study New Hospital -- PMM and Mr. Rauch's Letters, 1974-1978 (Box 7)
  - Hospital -- Duke North Official Statement Distribution Listing, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Highland Hospital (Box 7)
  - Hospital, Sea Level (Box 7)
  - Griffith Endowment A-D, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Griffith Endowment E-L, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Griffith Endowment M-V, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Griffith Endowment M-Z, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Academic Council -- University Bylaws (Box 8)
  - Academic Council -- Rosters, 1962-1975 (Box 8)
  - Academic Council Elections, 1965-1977 (Box 8)
  - Academic Council Ad Hoc Committee on Duke Athletics, 1969 (Box 8)
  - ACT-Erwin Neighborhood Council, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Administrative Council, 1966-1969 (Box 8)
  - Administrative Officers Summary, 1967-1975 (Box 8)
  - Administrative Officers Summary 1976-1977 (Box 9)
  - Honorary Degree Nominations and Committee, 1967-1980 [Restricted] (Box 9)
  - Honorary Degree Recipients, 1924-1968 (Box 9)
  - Trustee Correspondence A-G, 1952-1981 (Box 9)
  - Trustee Correspondence H-J, 1952-1981 (Box 9)
  - Trustee Correspondence K-O, 1952-1981 (Box 9)
  - Trustee Correspondence P-S, 1952-1981 (Box 9)
  - Trustee Correspondence T-V, 1952-1981 (Box 9)
  - Trustee Correspondence W-Z, 1952-1981 (Box 9)
  - Trustees University Stock Proxy Vote (Box 9)
  - Trustee Vacancies, Dates of Retirement, Expiring Terms, Etc. (Box 9)
  - Trustee Committees -- List and Letters of Appointments (Box 9)
  - Board of Trustees, Resolutions, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
  - Trustees Miscellaneous Material and Items (Box 10)
  - Trustee Disclosure and Conflict of Interest Statements, 1978-1983 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence A-F, 1967-1974 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence G-L, 1967-1974 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence M-R, 1967-1974 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence S-Z, 1967-1974 (Box 10)
  - Directions for Progress, Letters Regarding Department of Education, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Directions for Progress, Letters Regarding School of Nursing, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Directions for Progress, Letters Regarding East Campus Residential Life, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Directions for Progress, Materials Related to and Letters Regarding Health, Physical Education, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Nursing School, Letters Regarding Task Force Recommendations, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Letters to Trustees: Forestry (Box 10)
  - University Policy and Planning Advisory Committee, 1966-1968 (Box 11)
  - Committee on Education Administration, 1966-1972 (Box 11)
  - Building and Grounds Committee, 1966-1975 (Box 11)
  - Presidential Inaugural Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Committees of University (Box 11)
  - Past Standing Committee Rosters (Box 11)
  - President Deryl Hart (Box 12)
  - President Knight Correspondence to and from, 1966-1969 (Box 12)
  - President Terry Sanford, 1970-1985 (Box 12)
  - President's Report, 1917-1974 (Box 12)
  - Vice President for Public Relations, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Notice to Trustees re: Provost Appointment, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Vice President for Health Affairs, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Provost's Reports, 1967-1980 (Box 12)
  - Judicial Structure of the University (Watson Report), 1971 (Box 12)
  - Intercollegiate Athletics (Mr. Pye's Report to Trustees), 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Chancellor's Reports, 1969-1980 (Box 12)
  - IRS Information (Mr. Powell's Report), 1973 (Box 12)
  - Reports by Vice President Kreps, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Vice President for Business and Finance Reports, 1969-1976 (Box 12)
  - Coalition of Duke Student Leaders - Report, Student Run Organizations, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Deaths, 1967-1984 (Box 12)
  - Necrology (Box 12)
  - Nancy Hanks Memorial (Box 12)
  - Executive Approvals, Chart of, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Henney, R. B.-Secretary The Duke Endowment, 1967-1973 (Box 12)
  - Publications Board, 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - Employees, Nonacademic, 1965-1968 (Box 12)
  - Students-Miscellaneous Information (Box 12)
  - Federal Student Loan Legislation -- Memorandum, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Tuition - Ministers' Children, 1975-1978 (Box 12)
  - Research Projects, 1948-1989 (Box 12)
  - Business Administration, Grad. School of, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Art Museum, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Forest Lands -- Forestry, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Primate Facility, 1975 (Box 12)
  - School of Nursing, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Graduate School Program, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Family Practice Program, Dept of Community and Family Medicine, 1985 (Box 12)
  - African and Afro-American Studies, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Black Studies, 1975 (Box 13)
  - WDBS Radio Station, 1973 February 28-1974 September 20 (Box 13)
  - WDBS Radio Station, 1975 March 28-1976 March 26 (Box 13)
  - WDBS Radio Station, 1976 October 4-1978 March 17 (Box 13)
  - WDBS Radio Station, 1978 October 30-1980 April 23 (Box 13)
  - Picketing, Protests and Demonstrations, 1968-1969 (Box 13)
  - Plagiarism (Box 13)
  - Lawsuits -- Closed (Box 13)
  - Central Campus Housing (Box 13)
  - Married Student Housing (Box 13)
  - Redemption Authorization, Married Student Housing Bonds (Box 13)
  - Fifth Decade Campaign (Box 13)
  - 50th Anniversary Duke University Program of Events (Box 13)
  - Gross, Paul "Fifty Years of Duke University and the Duke Endowment" (Box 13)
  - Brodie, H. Keith H. Speech "Of Culture and Anarchy" (Box 13)
  - Pictures - Dr. Griffiths (Box 13)
  - Organ (Box 13)
  - Homesites, Duke (Box 13)
  - Gravesites, Duke University (Box 13)
  - Gazebo and Old Trinity Bell (Box 13)
  - Trinity Gazebo (Box 13)
  - Directory of Volunteers 1987-1994 (Box 14)
  - Class Directories: 1935, 1983, 1984 (Box 14)
  - South Africa/Apartheid Issue, 1977 (Box 14)
  - Academic Priorities Committee: Report on Graduate Education Fall 1986, 27 January 1987 (Box 15)
  - Commencement, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Commencement, 1995 (Box 15)
  - Commencement, 1996 (Box 15)
  - Child and Family Issues Committee, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Child and Family Issues Committee, Final Report, 1994 October (Box 15)
  - Child and Family Issues Committee, Draft Report, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Child and Family Issues Committee, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Child and Family Issues Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 15)
  - Eighth Edition Directory of Volunteers, 1994 August (Box 15)
  - Seventh Edition Directory of Volunteers, 1 July 1993 (Box 15)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1980-1995 (Box 15)
  - Duke Homestead (offer of to State by Univ.), 7 January 1972 (Box 16)
  - East-West Expressway, Crest Street (Box 16)
  - Duke Seminar, 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Taylor Cole, 1994 (Box 16)
  - Donor Recognition Task Force, Correspondence, 1988-1989, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Distinguished Alumni Award, 1997 December (Box 16)
  - Annual Faculty Meeting, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Emeriti Faculty Brochure, 1992-1993 (Box 16)
  - Crypt Committee, Chapel (Box 16)
  - Commencement, 1997 (Box 16)
  - COFHE Study, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Commencement, Ad Hoc Task Force, University Ceremonies, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Curriculum Review, 1986 (Box 16)
  - University Emeriti, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Faculty Emeriti (Faculty only) (Box 16)
  - Duke Marketing Study (Box 16)
  - Feasibility Study, 1993 (Box 16)
  - Honorary Degree Notebook, 1995 September-1997 February (Box 16)
- Accession UA2018.0047, 1982-2014; 1
  - Brodie, Pres. H. Keith, 1986-1992 (Box 17)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Personnel restriction until 2062.
  - No Title (Correspondence, Meeting Minutes from John Alexander McMahon, BOT), 1970s-1980s; 4 folders (Box 17)
    Personnel and Board of Trustees restrictions until 2059
  - Senior Leadship Retreat, 2004-2005 (Box 17)
    Administrative restriction until 2029.
  - Background Materials on Duke University, Duke University Medical Center, and DUHS (formerly binder), 2003 (Box 17)
    Administrative restriction until 2028.
  - Exhibits for Board of Trustees meetings, 1989-1994; 7 folders (Box 17)
    Board of Trustees restriction until 2044.
  - Board of Trustees Retreat Exhibit 1 (Volume B), December 2, 2000; 4 folders (Box 17)
    Board of Trustees restriction until 2050.
  - Research Volume 1, A-F, 1985-2005; 2 folders (Box 17)
    Board of Trustees restriction until 2055.
  - Research Volume II, G-M, 1985-2005; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Research Volume III, P-Z, 1985-2005; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Report from the Provost to the Board of Trustees, September 25, 1987 (Box 18)
    Board of Trustees restriction until 2037.
  - Duke University Board of Trustees Retreat at Stanford University, February 26-March 1, 2014 (Box 18)
    Board of Trustees restriction until 2064.
  - What Difference Does a Difference Make?: From a Symposium at Duke University, 1997; VHS (Box 18, Video-cassette UA04010001-VHS-0001)
  - 2003 Duke University Trustee Dinner, VHS (Box 18, Video-cassette UA04010001-VHS-0002)
    Board of Trustees restriction until 2053.
  - Backup of Trustee Laptop from University Secretary, 2008-01-23; Optical disc (Box 18, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0001)
    Board of Trustee restriction until 2058.
  - NAN Images, 2 discs; Optical disc (Box 18, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0002, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0003)
  - Computer Presentation Trustee Dinner, May 7, 2004; Optical disc (Box 18, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0004)
    Board of Trustees restriction until 2054.
  - Duke University Trustees Dinner, May 13, 2005; 2 discs; DVD (Box 18, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0005, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0006)
  - Duke Athletics Night, September 11, 2006; 2 discs; DVD (Box 18, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0007, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0008)
  - The Charlie Rose Show: Pres. Richard Brodhead, December 2005; 2 discs; DVD (Box 18, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0009, Optical-disc UA04010001-OP-0010)
- Accession UA2015-0057, 1960-2013 and undated
  Scope and Contents
  Includes correspondence, memoranda, research, clippings, and reports related to University Administration and the Board of Trustees.
  Access restricted. For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist. Contact Research Services for more information.
  Access restricted. Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees. Contact Research Services for more information.
  - Accreditation, undated (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2029.
  - Admissions, 1981-2004 (Box 19)
  - Affirmative Action Plan for Equal Opportunity, 1961-2007 (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2032.
  - Alcohol Policy/Substance Abuse, 1986-2000 (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2025.
  - Alma Mater, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Alumni Affairs, 2007 (Box 19)
  - Audit Committee Minutes, 2000-2007 (Box 19)
  - Articles About Duke, undated (Box 19)
  - Awards, 1978-2000 (Box 19)
  - Board Room, circa 1984 (Box 19)
    Board of Trustees records restricted until 2034.
  - John Burness, 1990-2004 (Box 19)
  - Campus Security, 2003 (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2028.
  - Certifications, 1993-1997 (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2027.
  - Chapel, Duke, 1970s-2005 (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2030.
  - Chronicle, 1994-2001 (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2026.
  - Commencement, 1998-2006 (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2031.
  - Confidentiality, Board Records, 1989-1995 (Box 19)
    Board of Trustees records restricted until 2045.
  - Distinguished Alumni Award, 1997-2005 (Box 19)
  - Documentary Studies, 2000-2003 (Box 19)
  - Duke Experience Survey, 1997 (Box 19)
  - Duke Family, undated (Box 19)
  - Duke History, undated (Box 19)
  - Endowment Minimums, 1983-2004 (Box 19)
  - Founders Day Committee, 1996-2013 (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2038.
  - Founders Society, 1988 (Box 19)
  - French Family Science Center, 2007 (Box 19)
  - Information Technology, 1997-2003 (Box 19)
  - Institutional Advancement Committee, 1996-2003 (Box 19)
  - Institutional Equity, 2004 (Box 19)
  - Institutional Reinvestment Account, 2003 (Box 19)
  - Investment Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 19)
  - Investment Policy, 1981-1994 (Box 19)
  - Keohane, Nan, undated (Box 19)
    Administrative records restricted until 2039.
  - Keohane, Clippings, undated (Box 19)
  - Knight, Douglas, 1966-2005 (Box 19)
  - Mailings, circa 2002-2005 (Box 19)
  - Medical Center Affairs Committee, 1978-1991 (Box 20)
  - Minutes - Archives, 1988 (Box 20)
  - Nomenclature Committee, 1989 (Box 20)
  - Officers Listing, 2004-2010 (Box 20)
    Administrative records restricted until 2035.
  - Organizational Charts, 1987-2004 (Box 20)
  - Palestinian Forum, 2004 (Box 20)
  - Presidential Council (Campus Culture Initiative), 2006-2007 (Box 20)
  - Presidential Portraits (Cleaning), 2005 (Box 20)
  - Publications Board, 1990-1993 (Box 20)
  - Putman University Professorship, 1999-2002 (Box 20)
  - Race Relations, 1982-2001 (Box 20)
  - Real Estate, 1960-1991 (Box 20)
  - Religious Edifices on Campus, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Residential Life, 1978-2001; 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Risk Assessment Committee, 2006 (Box 20)
  - ROTC, 1995-1998 (Box 20)
    Administrative records restricted until 2023.
  - Safety, 1987-2004 (Box 20)
  - Same Sex Partners, 1995-1998; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - SARS, 2003 (Box 20)
  - SCUUL (Schools, Colleges, University Underwriters), 1986 (Box 20)
  - South African Apartheid Social Implications Committee, 1972-2003 (Box 20)
  - Subcommittees of the Board, 1986-1995 (Box 20)
  - Substance Abuse, 1988-1989 (Box 20)
  - Trent, Josiah C. Memorial Foundation Bylaws, undated (Box 20)
  - Trustee Statistics, 1981-2001 (Box 20)
    Board of Trustees records restricted until 2051.
  - Trustee Surveys, 1991 (Box 20)
  - Terms and Vacancies, 1984-1992 (Box 20)
  - University Marshall, 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - Washington Duke Inn and Golf Club, 1994-2001 (Box 20)
  - Willimon Report "Old Duke--New Duke", 2000 (Box 20)
  - Woman's College Report, 2002 (Box 20)
  - Work Plan, 2001 (Box 20)